Ms. Yun?
Nona Yun?
Ms. Yun.
Nona Yun.
Is everything okay?
Semua baik?
I told you not to stay out late.
Kubilang jangan pulang larut.
You never listen to me, do you?
Kau tak pernah mendengarku.
It looks like you've lost some weight.
Sepertinya beratmu turun.
Your eyes look sunken too.
Matamu juga tampak cekung.
And what are these under your eyes?
Apa itu di bawah matamu?
Are they the thing called dark circles?
Apa itu lingkaran hitam?
I like you like this.
Aku suka kau seperti ini.
I was going to go back right away
Aku langsung kembali jika kau seperti freesia di musim semi.
I've warned you.
Aku peringatkan kau.
Once you fall for me,
Begitu kau menyukaiku...
there's no way out.
tak ada jalan keluar.
Let's go home.
Ayo pulang.
Ms. Descendant.
Nona Keturunan.
My gosh, I missed you.
Astaga, aku merindukanmu.
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
He's been given a new mission. We can come here when we're given a mission.
Dia diberi misi baru. Kami bisa kemari saat diberi misi.
A mission?
Misi?
What kind of mission?
Misi macam apa?
He has to find some kind of meaning, which sounds so tough.
Dia harus menemukan makna, itu terdengar sulit.
He has to have a revelation of some sort.
Harus mendapat semacam wahyu.
There's such a mission?
Ada misi seperti itu?
He's ridiculously stubborn.
Dia sangat keras kepala.
When we got to the Land of Water, the red tide had come four times.
Saat kami tiba di Negeri Air, gelombang merah datang empat kali.
Lord Habaek was having trouble adjusting to the new environment.
Tuan Habaek sulit menyesuaikan diri dengan lingkungan baru.
-What? "The new environment"? -Yes.
- Apa? Lingkungan baru? - Ya.
Things in the Land of Water are very different from here.
Hal-hal di Negeri Air sangat berbeda dari sini.
I see.
Aku mengerti.
Usually, you become just a little bit more sensitive.
Biasanya kau jadi agak lebih sensitif.
But Lord Habaek was awfully quiet, as if he was angry,
Tapi Tuan Habaek sangat diam seolah dia marah.
and he seemed listless.
Dan dia tampak lesu.
Then one day, he started pestering everyone.
Lalu suatu hari, dia mulai mengganggu semua orang.
Lord Habaek.
Tuan Habaek.
The High Priest is visiting the Land of the Sky at the moment,
Pendeta Agung mengunjungi Negeri Langit saat ini,
-but he left a message for you. -Which is?
- tapi punya pesan untukmu. - Apa?
He said finding out why the sacred stones are kept
Dia bilang mencari tahu kenapa batu suci
in the human world was not your mission.
disimpan di dunia manusia bukan misimu.
Must that old man keep being this stubborn?
Haruskah orang tua itu tetap keras kepala?
Back then, he made it sound very meaningful.
Saat itu, dia membuatnya terdengar sangat berarti.
As far as he remembers, you told him that you couldn't be bothered.
Seingatnya, kau bilang padanya kau tak bisa diganggu.
Right, I did. However,
Benar. Namun...
he told me again that I must find the answer to the question.
dia juga bilang aku harus temukan jawaban pertanyaan itu.
"It wasn't a question."
"Itu bukan pertanyaan."
From what he remembers, that was your answer.
Seingatnya, itu jawabanmu.
It was a question.
Itu sebuah pertanyaan.
Also, Lord Habaek will be our next emperor.
Juga, Tuan Habaek akan menjadi kaisar kita selanjutnya.
Why can't the High Priest just give in?
Kenapa Pendeta Agung tak menyerah?
Keep it up.
Teruskan.
Lord Habaek would like to find the answer.
Tuan Habaek ingin menemukan jawabannya.
I mean, have you ever seen him volunteering to do anything?
Kau pernah melihat dia ingin melakukan sesuatu sendiri?
That's what happened.
Itu yang terjadi.
Because he was so persistent,
Karena dia sangat gigih,
the High Priest finally managed to get permission to send him back here.
Pendeta Agung akhirnya dapat izin mengirimnya ke sini.
I wonder what he's trying to find, though.
Aku penasaran apa yang dia cari.
I see that Yongyong is here.
Yongyong di sini.
Well, it's...
Itu...
I didn't know you'd use a plush toy to satisfy your emotional needs.
Aku tak tahu kau pakai boneka untuk memuaskan kebutuhan emosionalmu.
That's not why it's here. It's...
Bukan karena itu di sini. Itu...
Did you pick on Yongyong?
Apa kau mengganggu Yongyong?
Did you abuse him?
Kau menyiksanya?
Or every night, when you were feeling lonely...
Atau di malam saat kau kesepian...
I hope you didn't do anything weird to him.
semoga kau tak berlaku aneh padanya.
Hey, don't be ridiculous.
Jangan konyol.
It's so much faster this way. Why did you always take a detour?
Lebih cepat seperti ini.
Nothing has changed.
Tak ada yang berubah.
I told you to clean the place often.
Kubilang bersihkan tempat ini.
It's harder to try to clean it after a long time.
Lebih sulit membersihkannya setelah sekian lama.
I told you to get a different light for your entrance.
Kubilang cari lampu baru untuk gerbang.
I also told you to eat well.
Kubilang juga makanlah dengan baik.
You haven't even canceled the phone contract.
Kau belum batalkan kontrak ponsel.
You never do what I tell you to do.
Kau tak pernah lakukan perintahku.
Anyway, how have you been?
Bagaimana kabarmu?
What are you trying to find here?
Apa yang kau cari di sini?
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
Namsuri said...
Namsuri berkata...
you've been given a new mission.
kau diberi misi baru.
I heard you have to find out why the sacred stones are kept here.
Kau harus cari tahu kenapa batu suci disimpan di sini.
I don't care about that.
Aku tak peduli itu.
I came back because I knew you weren't doing well.
Aku kembali karena aku tahu kau tak baik.
I...
Aku...
have to go back.
Aku harus kembali.
That's still the path I must take.
Masih ada jalan yang harus kuambil.
I came to say goodbye properly.
Aku mau kita berpisah baik-baik.
Properly.
Dengan benar.
I want to love you with no regrets.
Aku ingin mencintaimu tanpa penyesalan.
Even if we have to part ways,
Walau kita berpisah...
I want to be able to convince myself that I loved you enough.
aku ingin yakin bahwa aku cukup mencintaimu.
If you're not ready...
Jika kau tak siap...
If you don't agree with me...
Jika kau tak setuju denganku...
I'll just go back.
aku akan kembali.
So you want to love properly...
Kau mau mencintai dengan baik...
so that you can say a proper goodbye.
agar bisa berpisah baik-baik.
It doesn't make much sense,
Itu tak masuk akal...
but it still sounds very nice.
tapi masih terdengar bagus.
Looking back...
Melihat ke belakang,
I'm realizing that I've been too ungenerous to myself.
aku sadar aku sangat tidak baik pada diriku sendiri.
Who would have wanted to love me...
Siapa yang mau mencintaiku...
when I didn't love myself?
jika aku tak mencintai diriku?
Someone must have felt sorry for me.
Pasti ada yang kasihan kepadaku.
That's why I got lucky like this.
Itu sebabnya aku beruntung.
It's because you're a nice person.
Karena kau orang yang baik.
I'm not nice.
- Aku tidak baik. - Baik.
Fine.
Baiklah.
It's not easy to be nice when you live in a world like this.
Tak mudah bersikap baik saat kau di dunia seperti ini.
"All that a nice person ever gets is a decent guy." Is that the lesson?
"Orang baik akan mendapat pria yang baik." Apa itu pelajarannya?
A story like that wouldn't even sell these days.
Kisah seperti itu kini tak laku.
Am I just a decent guy?
Apa aku hanya pria baik?
I'm a god.
Aku dewa.
Then...
Kalau begitu...
"A nice person gets to meet a god." Is that the lesson?
"Orang baik bisa bertemu dewa." Apa itu pelajarannya?
Do you think that's enough?
Kau pikir itu cukup?
Then...
Lalu...
what else?
apa lagi?
Something like this.
Seperti ini.
HABAEK YUN SO-A
HABAEK, YUN SO-A
Just help her forget Habaek.
Bantu dia lupakan Habaek.
That's not something I can easily do.
Itu tidak mudah.
Give it a try.
Cobalah.
You were planning on doing that anyway.
Kau berencana melakukannya.
That is not...
Itu bukan...
something I can easily do.
hal yang mudah.
Ms. Descendant.
Nona Keturunan.
Why are you coming out of that room?
Kenapa kau keluar dari kamar itu?
What?
Apa?
Well, I...
Aku...
I was just looking for something.
Aku hanya mencari sesuatu.
What were you looking for?
Apa yang kau cari?
Never mind.
Lupakan saja.
-What were you looking for? -Oh, nothing. Don't mind me.
- Kau mencari apa? - Bukan apa-apa. Lupakan.
Were you looking for me?
Kau mencariku?
I'm going to work part-time starting today.
Aku kerja paruh waktu mulai hari ini.
I called the owner of the duck boat tour company earlier,
Tadi kutelepon pemilik perahu bebek
and he wants to meet right away.
dan dia ingin bertemu.
He was so sad when I told him that you couldn't work there anymore.
Dia sedih saat kubilang kau tak bisa bekerja di sana lagi.
Don't you have to go to work?
Bukankah kau harus bekerja?
No. My clinic will be closed for a little while.
Tidak. Klinikku akan ditutup sebentar.
What? Why?
Apa? Kenapa?
Some stuff happened.
Ada hal yang terjadi.
It's a good thing, though.
Itu bagus.
I live with an omnipotent god. Why should I work so hard to earn money?
Aku bersama dewa yang mahakuasa.
Let me benefit from your amazing powers now.
Biar aku menikmati kuasamu yang luar biasa.
-He doesn't have any. -Sorry?
- Dia tak punya. - Apa?
-He doesn't have any powers. -What?
- Dia tak punya kekuatan.
You still haven't gotten them back?
Kau masih belum mendapatkannya?
You said they'd come back when you returned to the divine realm.
Kau bilang akan kembali saat kembali ke alam dewa.
-They did. -And?
- Benar. - Lalu?
-He left them there. -What?
- Dia tinggalkan di sana. - Apa?
Leave what?
Meninggalkan apa?
-I can't take my powers with me? -Correct.
- Tak bisa bawa kekuatanku? - Ya.
He said you'll have to leave exactly how you came back
Katanya kau harus pergi seperti kau kembali
if you wish to return to the human world that much.
jika ingin kembali ke dunia manusia.
But why? Why does he have to do that?
Tapi kenapa? Kenapa begitu?
He said that's only fair.
Dia bilang itu adil.
"Fair"?
Adil?
Fair for whom?
Adil bagi siapa?
He said there will be no more negotiations,
Katanya tak ada negosiasi,
-but... -What?
- tapi... - Apa?
You won't accomplish the mission anyway,
Kau tak akan menyelesaikan misinya,
so he'll put a precautionary measure in place
jadi, dia beri tindakan pencegahan
because you have to come back for the coronation ceremony.
karena kau harus kembali untuk upacara penobatan.
"A precautionary measure"?
Pencegahan?
He said that he'll allow you to use your abilities just once
Dia akan mengizinkanmu
so that you can open the Divine Gate and return.
untuk membuka Gerbang Suci dan kembali.
When the sixth red tide comes,
Saat gelombang merah keenam tiba,
he'll send a messenger to you.
dia akan mengirim utusan.
-What? -"Don't go if you don't like the terms."
- Apa? - "Tinggallah jika tak suka syaratnya."
He also said that.
Dia juga mengatakan itu.
That's what happened.
Itu yang terjadi.
Are they a lunch bag or what? How can you just leave them there?
Apa itu tas makan siang? Bagaimana bisa kau tinggalkan?
By the way, why did you lose your powers in the first place?
Tapi kenapa kau kehilangan kekuatanmu?
I've asked him a few times,
Aku tanyakan beberapa kali,
but he just kept giving me creepy smirks.
tapi dia hanya memberiku seringai.
He just said it can happen. He was so vague about it.
Katanya itu bisa terjadi. Sangat misterius.
Then...
Lalu…
are you saying you came back empty-handed?
Maksudmu kau kembali dengan tangan kosong?
No, with hunger.
Dengan rasa lapar.
Don't worry. Those in the Land of Water aren't that heartless.
Jangan khawatir.
I was told that I could take
Aku bisa bawa satu hal
one thing that's most needed in the human world except for my powers,
yang paling dibutuhkan di sini, kecuali kekuatanku. Aku bawa.
Something like a magic wand? Can it make gold and silver?
Seperti tongkat sihir?
It's much more...
Sebenarnya jauh...
powerful than that.
lebih hebat dari itu.
Namsuri.
Namsuri.
RESIDENT REGISTRATION CARD, NAMSURI DRIVER'S LICENSE, HABAEK
KARTU IDENTITAS, NAMSURI SIM, HABAEK
What is that?
Apa itu?
No way.
Tidak mungkin.
-A driver's license? -Mine is a resident registration card.
- Izin mengemudi? - Punyaku kartu identitas.
Now, I'll do all the driving.
Kini aku akan mengemudi.
Now, I'm legally allowed to work.
Kini aku bisa bekerja secara legal.
-What is it? -Answer the call.
- Ada apa? - Jawablah.
Stop bothering Mr. Kim so much. Don't you feel bad for him?
Berhenti merepotkan Pak Kim.
He's the protagonist of his own life.
Dia adalah protagonis dalam hidupnya.
And if his life were a movie,
Jika hidupnya adalah film...
you'd only be a supporting character. A mean one.
kau karakter pendukung yang jahat.
Don't say that he earns a living thanks to you.
Jangan bilang dia bisa kerja berkat kau.
Thanks to your staff,
Berkat stafmu,
you can lounge around like this.
kau bisa bersantai seperti ini.
You guys are all doing what each other can't do.
Kalian melakukan yang tak bisa dilakukan satu sama lain.
-What's wrong with you? -Nothing.
- Kau kenapa? - Tak ada.
I guess it's because of what I saw.
Mungkin karena yang kulihat.
I saw humans talking about things like that on TV yesterday.
Kulihat manusia membicarakan hal seperti itu di TV kemarin.
Answer it.
Jawablah.
What do you want?
Apa maumu?
What is it, Mr. Kim?
Ada apa, Pak Kim?
Please tell Biryeom that I'm so grateful for his help.
Tolong sampaikan Biryeom aku berterima kasih atas bantuannya.
Thank you very much, Biryeom.
Terima kasih banyak, Biryeom.
The director said that you can shoot the kissing scene again
Sutradara bilang kau bisa syuting adegan ciuman lagi
when you're ready. He said he can wait.
saat kau siap. Katanya dia menunggu.
Tell Biryeom...
Sampaikan Biryeom...
Let him know that--
Katakan padanya...
Hello?
Halo?
I'm not done. How can she hang up on me?
Aku belum selesai. Teganya dia?
Let's have lunch. I made a reservation at the new restaurant.
Ayo makan siang.
Life is all about enjoying good food and drink.
Hidup adalah menikmati makanan dan minuman enak.
It sounds like you might end up staying here for good.
Tampaknya kau akan di sini selamanya.
The humans I saw on TV yesterday said
Manusia di TV kemarin berkata
that no one exists for someone else. But they're wrong
tak ada yang hidup demi orang lain.
Is that so? Is that why you sold the land and traveled the world for ten years?
Benarkah?
I came back from time to time and entertained you.
Aku kembali sesekali dan menghiburmu.
Oh, did you hate that I was away for a long time?
Apa kau benci aku pergi untuk waktu lama?
No. Of course not.
Tidak. Tentu tidak.
Things are so peaceful between us now that Habaek is gone.
Kita begitu damai setelah Habaek pergi.
I should've sent him back a long time ago.
Harusnya kupulangkan dia dulu.
You look gorgeous enough now, so just get changed. Do nothing else.
Kau cantik, gantilah baju saja.
Goodbye,
Selamat tinggal,
my love.
Cintaku.
Don't come back again.
Jangan kembali lagi.
Don't ask the forest for directions.
Jangan tanya arah pada hutan.
Don't send your regards through the wind.
Jangan kirim salammu lewat angin.
I'll just remember...
Aku akan ingat...
that you were my everything.
kau dulu segalanya bagiku.
Why didn't you knock?
Kenapa tak mengetuk pintu?
It looks like you'll be traumatized by it.
Sepertinya kau trauma.
-What are you going to do? -Trauma, my foot.
- Apa yang akan kau lakukan? - Trauma apanya.
I'm the greatest goddess of the Land of Water, Mura.
Aku dewi terhebat Negeri Air, Mura.
I can't watch you go through this.
Aku tak bisa melihatmu begini.
Let me help you.
Biar kubantu.
All right. That's how it feels.
Baiklah. Seperti itu rasanya.
Remember that feeling.
Ingat perasaan itu.
-Then you'll get out of your slump. -Hey!
- Kau tak akan terpuruk lagi. - Hai!
Why are you being like this?
Kenapa kau seperti ini?
It looks like you keep forgetting the fact that I'm your fiancé.
Sepertinya kau terus lupa
You'd better not say that word, "fiancé," ever again.
Sebaiknya jangan sebut kata tunangan lagi.
What are you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
You begged me to be your fiancé.
Kau memohon aku jadi tunanganmu.
Have you changed your mind?
Kau berubah pikiran?
When did I beg you?
Kapan aku memohon?
You wanted me to tell Habaek that we're engaged.
Kau ingin aku beri tahu Habaek kita bertunangan.
You were jealous of that girl, Shim Chong.
Kau cemburu pada gadis itu, Shim Chong.
When I told Habaek,
Saat kuberi tahu Habaek,
he congratulated us. Don't you remember?
dia memberi selamat. Kau lupa?
Back then, I even broke up with a girl
Saat itu, aku bahkan putus dengan seorang gadis
to accommodate that request of yours.
karena permintaanmu itu.
She was the prettiest girl in the Land of the Sky.
Dia gadis tercantik Negeri Langit.
That was...
Itu...
You weren't that into her anyway.
Kau tak begitu suka padanya.
And everyone knows that you're a player.
Semua orang tahu kau suka main-main.
Come on.
Ayolah.
This "player" has a heart too.
Pemain ini juga punya hati.
Let go. I said, let go!
Lepaskan. Kubilang, lepas!
Without Habaek, it's so peaceful here.
Tanpa Habaek, tempat ini sangat damai.
Why do you keep acting like you don't know how I feel about you?
Kenapa kau bersikap seolah tak tahu perasaanku?
Gosh.
Astaga.
It's not easy to put on an act for so long,
Tidak mudah untuk berakting begitu lama.
and it's certainly not easy to play along for this long.
Tak mudah untuk ikut berakting begitu lama.
But somehow, this setup has been working.
Tapi entah bagaimana, ini berhasil.
Let's get something to eat.
Ayo makan.
Don't hit me, please.
Jangan pukul aku.
It hurts.
Rasanya sakit.
Don't talk to me.
Jangan bicara denganku.
Goodness.
Astaga.
Did I do it again?
Aku melakukannya lagi?
Yes, you did. You're in worse shape than last time.
Ya, benar. Kondisimu lebih buruk dari sebelumnya.
I'm sorry...
Aku minta maaf...
for being such a bother.
sudah merepotkan.
Is it because of the girl?
Apa karena gadis itu?
I don't know why I keep reaching out to you for help when I have my secretary.
Entah kenapa aku terus minta bantuanmu padahal ada sekretarisku.
This won't happen again.
Ini tak akan terjadi lagi.
When the King ordered me to take you away from your mother,
Saat Raja memerintahkanku untuk mengambilmu dari ibumu,
I really didn't want to do it.
aku tak mau melakukannya.
The same goes for when he ordered me to imprison you in that cave.
Sama seperti saat dia menyuruhku mengurungmu di gua itu.
But there wasn't much I could do as a powerless lowly deity.
Tapi tak banyak yang bisa kulakukan sebagai dewa rendah tak berdaya.
I tried to just ignore you, but it wasn't easy.
Aku mencoba mengabaikanmu, tapi itu tak mudah.
As a human baby, you were so little and weak.
Sebagai bayi manusia, kau sangat kecil dan lemah.
I hoped you'd just die on your own.
Kuharap kau mati sendiri.
But eventually,
Tapi akhirnya,
I realized that you're half mortal and half immortal,
aku sadar kau manusia setengah dewa.
which means you'd always be alone.
Berarti kau akan selalu sendiri.
You'd always be lonely, imprisoned in that cave forever.
Kau akan selalu kesepian, terkurung di gua itu selamanya.
I felt sorry for you and scared.
Aku merasa bersalah dan takut.
Part of me wanted to abandon you,
Sebagian diriku ingin meninggalkanmu
and another part of me wanted to save you.
dan sebagian lagi ingin menyelamatkanmu.
I tried so hard not to become attached to you.
Aku berusaha keras untuk tak terikat padamu.
Whenever I visited you at the cave,
Setiap kali aku mengunjungimu di gua,
I told you about the world of gods, but it wasn't for your sake.
aku ceritakan dunia dewa, tapi itu bukan demi kebaikanmu.
I did it for my own sake.
Itu demi aku sendiri.
And I came here to avoid you.
Dan aku datang kemari untuk menghindarimu.
But...
Tapi...
it didn't work out.
itu tak berhasil.
The whole cave was already inside me,
Seluruh gua sudah dalam diriku
and you were still cowering in it.
dan kau masih gemetar ketakutan di dalamnya.
I'd like to...
Aku ingin...
show you a hidden part of me.
tunjukkan bagian tersembunyi diriku.
In the human world,
Di dunia manusia,
even beggars have to care about their looks. That's why I wear it,
pengemis harus peduli penampilan. Karena itu aku memakainya,
but it's so uncomfortable.
tapi ini sangat tidak nyaman.
You look much better without it.
Kau lebih baik tanpa itu.
Do you want a piece of advice?
Kau mau nasihat?
Show her who you are.
Tunjukkan siapa dirimu padanya.
Let her know who you really are.
Biarkan dia tahu siapa dirimu sebenarnya.
Like this. That's how everything begins.
Seperti ini. Begitulah semuanya dimulai.
If it doesn't work out even after you show her everything,
Jika tak berhasil bahkan setelah kau tunjukkan segalanya,
that means...
itu berarti...
you two aren't meant to be together.
kalian tidak berjodoh.
Hey, wait.
Hai, tunggu.
Why is a car so important?
Kenapa mobil begitu penting?
How could you do this to me? I jumped through hoops...
Teganya kau begini padaku?
to bring this here.
membawa ini ke sini.
Why bother bringing it?
Kenapa repot-repot membawanya?
You should've brought a magic wand instead.
Seharusnya kau bawa tongkat sihir.
I wanted to drive. Legally, like you said.
Aku ingin menyetir. Secara legal, seperti katamu.
Let's just run instead.
Ayo kita lari saja.
Let's run along the Han River starting tomorrow.
Di samping Sungai Han mulai besok.
Unbelievable.
Sulit dipercaya.
A man can't love without a car.
Pria tak bisa mencintai tanpa mobil.
What did you say?
Apa katamu?
What kind of nonsense is that?
Omong kosong macam apa itu?
Hey!
Hai.
Where does that distorted view come from?
Dari mana asal pikiran itu?
-What happened? -I've been given a new mission.
- Apa yang terjadi? - Aku diberi misi baru.
Don't be ridiculous.
Jangan konyol.
It might come in handy for you as well. You can use it when you need it.
Mungkin berguna juga bagimu. Kau bisa pakai saat kau butuh.
I can't believe you.
Tak bisa dipercaya.
Did you really have to do this?
Kau harus melakukan ini?
How could you do this to Mura?
Teganya kau lakukan ini pada Mura?
I know what she's worried about.
Aku tahu yang dia cemaskan.
Then...
Lalu..
-can't you at least act like you listen? -There are things I must decide on my own.
bisa kau pura-pura dengar?
Don't tell me you're not going back.
Jangan bilang kau tak kembali.
You know full well what will happen if you don't go back.
Kau tahu betul apa yang akan terjadi jika kau tak kembali.
I will go back.
Aku akan kembali.
Why is Mura...
Kenapa Mura...
-not enough for you? -Don't insult her.
- tak cukup bagimu? - Jangan menghinanya.
I know that you don't even mean it.
Aku tahu kau tak bersungguh-sungguh.
Why don't you muster up more courage instead of testing me like this?
Kenapa kau tak lebih berani daripada mengujiku seperti ini?
I wish hatred were allowed in the divine realm as well.
Kuharap kebencian diizinkan di alam suci juga.
Then you'd be my sworn enemy.
Kau jadi musuh bebuyutanku.
I'll think about it when I ascend the throne.
Kupikirkan saat naik takhta.
I'll look forward to it.
Aku menantikannya.
I hope we'll meet again as enemies.
Kuharap kita bertemu lagi sebagai musuh.
Are you okay?
Apa kau baik?
You're actually not smart at all.
Kau memang bodoh.
I'm not on your side.
Aku tidak di sisimu maupun Habaek.
I'll do what Mura wants.
Aku lakukan yang Mura inginkan.
I'm the one...
Akulah yang melakukan itu kepada keluargamu.
Mura was seething because of your ancestor,
Mura marah karena nenek moyangmu,
-so I took a little revenge. -What?
- jadi, aku balas dendam. - Apa?
Just hope that Mura is not as angry as she was back then.
Semoga Mura tidak semarah dia dulu.
Things are much simpler here than in the world of gods.
Di sini hal-hal lebih sederhana daripada di dunia para dewa.
Why did you talk to that good-for-nothing for so long?
Kenapa kau bicara dengannya begitu lama?
Did you order?
Sudah pesan?
I asked them for this black water.
- Kuminta air hitam ini. - Mereka paham?
They seemed to understand.
Sepertinya mengerti.
Is this what you came here for?
Itu alasanmu kemari?
I can't say this wasn't the reason at all.
Aku tak sepenuhnya menyangkalnya.
-So? Can you get your car back? -It's gone.
- Bisa ambil mobilmu kembali? - Hilang.
That's great.
Itu bagus.
I asked for a new car.
Aku meminta mobil baru.
I told them I wanted to drive the car today.
Kubilang mau pakai hari ini.
What?
Apa?
And? What did they say?
Apa kata mereka?
-They said it's not possible. -Of course it's not.
- Mereka bilang tidak bisa. - Tentu saja.
I'm shocked.
Aku terkejut.
I can't believe you can't buy a car as easily as you buy clothes.
Aku tak percaya kau tak bisa membeli mobil semudah pakaian.
Have you become a complete idiot or what?
Apa kau jadi orang bodoh?
I asked him to make me one using his powers.
Kuminta dia membuatkanku memakai kekuatannya.
That's ridiculous. Are you a kid?
Itu konyol. Apa kau anak kecil?
Anyway, what did he say to that?
Lalu apa katanya?
He refused.
Dia menolak.
But he said he'll go to a car dealership where he's a VIP client--
Tapi dia akan ke dealer mobil, di mana dia klien VIP...
What's going on?
Ada apa?
She is Habaek's woman.
Dia wanita Habaek.
I was...
Aku...
one step too late.
terlambat satu langkah.
He's the King.
Dia rajanya.
I can...
Aku tak akan...
never change that.
bisa mengubah itu.
I can't help...
Aku hanya...
but feel insecure.
merasa cemas.
When I found out that he left,
Saat aku tahu dia pergi,
I secretly...
diam-diam aku...
started feeling confident.
mulai merasa percaya diri.
His limitations...
Keterbatasannya...
are very different from mine, which is a huge relief.
sangat berbeda denganku, yang membuatku sangat lega.
But...
Tapi...
he's back.
dia kembali.
Jugeollin?
Jugeollin?
-What are you trying to do? -I'm trying...
- Apa yang kau lakukan? - Aku mau...
to lift the curse I put on you.
Aku berusaha hilangkan kutukanku padamu.
Then you should've told me. Why suddenly run at me like that?
Beru tahu aku dulu. Kenapa kau berlari?
I apologize.
Aku minta maaf.
Come on. Lift the curse and be on your way.
Ayo. Angkat kutukanmu dan pergilah.
Does that mean...
Apa itu berarti...
you haven't got your powers back yet?
kau belum mendapatkan kekuatanmu?
All right, then. Here it comes.
Baiklah. Ini dia.
No!
Tidak!
She's right. This is crazy. I can't do it.
Dia benar. Ini gila.
I'm used to hunger. Living like this isn't too bad, so just leave me alone.
Aku terbiasa merasa lapar.
-Sorry? -And mark my words.
- Apa? - Ingat ini.
Further down the road,
Suatu saat nanti,
I'll be sure to teach you a serious lesson.
aku akan memberimu pelajaran serius.
Hey.
Hai.
-We got a car. -What?
- Kita dapat mobil. - Apa?
What does it mean to have the eyes of the cat in Shrek?
Apa artinya memiliki mata kucing di Shrek?
He said he smiled at the woman who came to pick up the car with such eyes
Katanya dia tersenyum
Jingeon.
Jingeon.
Find out where Mura is now.
Cari Mura sekarang.
He lost... his powers?
Dia kehilangan...
That's right.
Benar.
He's been without his powers ever since he came here.
Dia tak punya kekuatan sejak dia datang kemari.
I didn't think you needed to know. That's why I've kept my mouth shut.
Kurasa kau tak perlu tahu.
How is it possible for a god to lose his powers?
Bagaimana mungkin dewa kehilangan kekuatan?
That's what I'm saying.
Itu maksudku.
This is what I think, though.
Ini yang kupikirkan.
It might be an ordeal
Mungkin ini cobaan yang harus dia hadapi untuk naik takhta.
New kings must go through tests when they're here to find the sacred stones,
Raja baru harus melalui ujian saat menemukan batu suci,
but we have no way of knowing what they actually experience.
tapi kita tak tahu apa yang mereka alami.
So? What is it that you want to say?
Jadi?
This is the human world, not the divine realm.
Ini dunia manusia, bukan alam suci.
Think about it carefully.
Pikirkan baik-baik.
Between you and a god who has lost all his abilities,
Antara kau dan dewa yang kehilangan kemampuannya,
who do you think has more?
siapa lebih baik?
And who do you think can be stronger?
Menurutmu siapa yang lebih kuat?
Darn it!
Sial!
Jugeollin?
Jugeollin?
Lady Mura, it's nice to see you here.
Nona Mura, senang melihatmu di sini.
What brings you here?
Kenapa kau kemari?
Well, I should get going.
Aku harus pergi.
Do the two of you know each other?
Apa kalian saling mengenal?
What brings you here?
Kenapa kau kemari?
Gosh, why is Lady Mura here?
Astaga, kenapa Nona Mura di sini?
Is that Lord Biryeom?
Itu Tuan Biryeom?
-Habaek is back. -I am aware.
- Habaek kembali. - Aku tahu.
You are?
Benarkah?
How do you know?
Kok bisa?
It looks like you caught those two in the act.
Tampaknya kau menangkap basah mereka.
What were they like?
Seperti apa mereka?
Were they all over each other?
Apa mereka bermesraan?
Forget it.
Lupakan.
That's not important now.
Itu tak penting saat ini.
Listen up.
Dengar.
The war begins now, and I'm on your side.
Perang dimulai sekarang dan aku di pihakmu.
-You're on my side? -That's correct. Your ally.
- Kau di pihakku? - Itu benar. Sekutumu.
The greatest goddess of the Land of Water has got your back.
Dewi terhebat Negeri Air mendukungmu.
If you can't win her heart,
Jika tak bisa memenangkan hatinya, ambil secara paksa.
Do whatever it takes to quarantine her. From Habaek, that is.
Lakukan apa pun untuk mengarantina dia dari Habaek.
"By force"?
Dengan paksa?
That's one dangerous remark.
Itu pernyataan berbahaya.
And...
Apakah...
is she suffering from a contagious disease or what?
dia mengidap penyakit menular?
Why "quarantine" her?
Kenapa karantina?
Habaek is not an easy target, of course.
Habaek bukan sasaran mudah, tentu saja.
I'll help you, though.
Aku akan membantumu.
I heard he lost all his powers.
Kudengar dia kehilangan kekuatannya.
Your future king.
Raja masa depanmu.
What?
Apa?
-What are you saying-- -Without his powers, he's nothing special.
- Apa... - Tanpa kekuatan, dia bukan apa-apa.
That means I must be stronger than him here.
Berarti aku lebih kuat darinya di sini.
-What did you just say? -I don't need your help.
- Apa katamu? - Aku tak butuh bantuanmu.
Please remain neutral.
Tetaplah netral.
If you guys use your powers to help him,
Jika kalian menggunakan kekuatan untuknya,
I'll have no choice but to use mine as well.
aku tak punya pilihan selain memakai kekuatanku.
But...
Tapi...
let's not do that to each other.
mari jangan lakukan itu.
Having to use my powers in the human world...
Memakai kekuatan di dunia manusia...
is one of the things that I absolutely despise.
adalah hal yang kubenci.
What are you doing here?
Sedang apa kau di sini?
Let's go.
Ayo.
How dare you touch her with that filthy hand?
Beraninya kau menyentuhnya dengan tangan itu?
Hey!
Hai!
I've learned to tame my temper as she nagged me so much about it.
Aku belajar tenang karena dia mengomeliku.
So you'd better lie low and hide like a rat.
Sebaiknya kau bersembunyi seperti tikus.
I won't bother you if you keep out of sight.
Aku tak mengganggumu jika kau tak tampak.
What the hell!
Apa-apaan.
Come here.
Kemarilah.
Let go!
Lepaskan!
Mr. Shin and I were just talking.
Pak Shin dan aku hanya bicara.
He held my hand because I was about to fall.
Dia memegang tanganku karena aku akan jatuh.
What is the matter with you?
Ada apa denganmu?
Don't talk to him.
Jangan bicara dengannya.
-He's not one of us. -It's true that he's different.
- Dia bukan kaum kita. - Ya, dia berbeda.
Like you said,
Seperti katamu...
he's a halfie.
dia makhluk separuh.
I understand why you hate him and look down on him.
Aku paham kenapa kau benci dan merendahkannya.
But can't you just think of him as one of those lowly humans?
Tak bisakah kau anggap dia manusia rendahan?
Are you doing this out of fear?
Apa karena kau takut?
The God of Death?
Dewa Kematian?
There's no such thing.
Tak ada hal semacam itu.
The stories we heard as kids are just folklore.
Kisah masa kecil itu hanya cerita rakyat.
Fine.
Baik.
I get your fear
Aku paham kau takut
because you're still so immature. But the thing is...
karena kau belum dewasa. Masalahnya...
I honestly can't understand your rage.
aku tak bisa memahami kemarahanmu.
There must be another reason.
Pasti ada alasan lain.
Until you tell me everything honestly,
Sampai kau mengatakan sejujurnya,
I won't be able to...
aku tak akan bisa...
accept these behaviors of yours.
menerima perilakumu.
What is it?
Apa itu?
What's the reason?
Apa alasannya?
Tell me the real reason!
Katakan!
Can't you see that I can't tell you because it's you?
Apa kau tak paham ini karena kau?
Because you're the one asking me for an explanation...
Karena kau meminta penjelasanku...
I can't tell you because it's you.
tak bisa kukatakan demi kau.
What? Come again?
Apa? Ulangi lagi?
Why? What does that mean?
Kenapa? Apa artinya?
Must you get that prick involved in this?
Apa kau harus melibatkan berengsek itu?
Do you have to resolve the thing with Habaek like this?
Harus selesaikan masalah Habaek seperti ini?
Then I'll seduce that girl, So-a, for you.
Akan kurayu So-a untukmu.
Shall I do that?
Haruskah kulakukan?
I can definitely distract her.
Aku pasti bisa mengalihkan dia.
It's my specialty, you know.
Itu keahlianku.
You're really helpless.
Kau benar-benar payah.
You had to make me slap you, didn't you?
Kau membuatku menamparmu, ya?
Jingeon.
Jingeon.
Jingeon!
Jingeon!
Tell me why Biryeom is acting that way.
Kenapa Biryeom seperti itu?
Tell me what you know.
Katakan yang kau tahu.
If you don't, I'm really going to freeze and crush your tongue.
Jika tidak, aku akan bekukan dan hancurkan lidahmu.
Tell me why he's going bonkers!
Katakan kenapa dia jadi gila!
It's because of me.
Itu karena aku.
-What? -That is all I can tell you.
- Apa? - Hanya itu yang bisa kukatakan.
As for my tongue, do as you wish.
Untuk lidahku, lakukan yang kau inginkan.
I read on the internet that you need to break in a new car
Aku baca di Internet kau perlu membobol mobil baru
by driving it on a highway.
dengan mengendarainya di jalan raya.
-Shall we go right now? -No.
- Kita lakukan sekarang? - Tidak.
Please slow down.
Tolong pelan-pelan.
I have a driver's license, so I can violate the speed limit now.
Aku punya SIM, bisa melanggar batas kecepatan.
What?
Apa?
Your driver's license doesn't give you the right to do that.
SIM tidak memberimu hak untuk melakukan itu.
Really? Then what is it for?
Sungguh? Lalu untuk apa?
It only gives you the right to drive.
Hanya hak mengemudi.
I knew that already. I was just joking.
Aku tahu. Aku bercanda.
Gosh.
Astaga.
Why would you make such a foolish joke?
Kenapa lawakanmu bodoh seperti itu?
Why were you so obsessed with getting a license?
Kenapa kau terobsesi dapat SIM?
You said you'd only feel safe if I had a driver's license.
Katamu kau merasa aman jika aku punya SIM.
I personally didn't care about having one, but I didn't want to make you feel uneasy.
Aku sendiri tak peduli,
HABAEK YUN SO-A
HABAEK, YUN SO-A
Are you upset?
Kau marah?
We can do it another day.
Kita bisa lakukan lain kali.
You're a little too excited today.
Kau terlalu bersemangat hari ini.
And as for me...
Dan bagiku...
I...
Aku...
I'd like to calmly look at you like this.
Aku mau melihatmu dengan tenang seperti ini.
Is this real? Or am I dreaming?
Apa ini nyata? Aku sedang bermimpi?
Is this really happening?
Ini sungguh terjadi?
Or is it just a dream?
Atau hanya mimpi?
Is this real?
Apa ini nyata?
Or am I dreaming?
Atau aku bermimpi?
If this is a dream,
Jika ini mimpi,
I hope I never wake up.
aku tak mau bangun.
It's real.
Ini nyata.
You're right.
Kau benar.
-This isn't fun. -Right, it isn't.
- Ini tak menyenangkan. - Benar.
We shouldn't do things that are not fun.
Jangan lakukan hal tak menyenangkan.
Good idea.
Ide bagus.
Where are you planning to go for a drive tomorrow?
Ke mana kau berkendara besok?
Should we go see the sunset?
Kita lihat matahari terbenam?
"The sunset"?
Matahari terbenam?
The sunrise and sunset. People purposely go to places to watch it.
Matahari terbit dan terbenam.
I always used to say it's pointless.
Selalu kubilang itu tak berguna.
What's the big deal about seeing a sunrise or sunset?
Apa penting melihatnya terbit atau terbenam?
Why would you climb a mountain when you need to come down again?
Kenapa mendaki gunung padahal harus turun lagi?
There's nothing special about the sea. It's just a large body of water.
Tak ada yang istimewa dari laut. Hanya banyak air.
That's what I said to my students when I was a private tutor.
Itu yang kukatakan kepada muridku saat aku menjadi tutor pribadi.
I also said that to the editor-in-chief when I worked as a part-time translator.
Juga kepada kepala editor
I said the same thing to a restaurant manager,
Aku juga mengatakan hal yang sama kepada
a department store manager,
manajer mal
and the owner of a convenience store where I worked.
dan pemilik toserba tempatku dulu bekerja.
Who else did I say that to?
Siapa lagi, ya?
Anyway, that's what I used to say to everyone all my life.
Itu yang sering kukatakan pada semua orang sepanjang hidupku.
And my conclusion was moving to Vanuatu.
Kesimpulanku, pindah ke Vanuatu.
But that's not going to happen.
Itu tak akan terjadi.
Tell me every place you want to visit.
Sebutkan tempat yang ingin kau kunjungi.
Tell me where you want to go and what you want to do.
Katakan ke mana dan apa yang ingin kau lakukan.
Why? Will you make it happen?
Kenapa? Kau akan wujudkan?
-Of course. -Oh, my.
- Tentu saja. - Astaga.
You know what, though?
Tapi apa kau tahu?
You need money to do all those things.
Kau butuh uang untuk melakukan semua itu.
We're both jobless. How can we afford to do anything?
Kita berdua menganggur.
Gosh, that's why you should've brought a magic wand.
Itu sebabnya kau harus membawa tongkat sihir.
Don't call me!
Jangan telepon aku!
I need money.
Aku butuh uang.
A lot of money.
Uang yang banyak.
Oh, I guess that man was you.
Kukira pria itu adalah kau.
Is So-a not here with you?
Apa So-a tidak denganmu?
What? No, she isn't.
Apa? Tidak.
But why are you always with her?
Tapi kenapa selalu bersamanya?
Pardon? When was I with her?
Apa? Kapan aku bersamanya?
Why did you two come here together soaked in rain the other day?
Kenapa kalian datang basah kuyup kemarin?
What is the meaning of it?
Apa artinya itu?
At first, I thought the owner of those sneakers would be Water...
Awalnya kupikir pemilik sepatu itu Iblis...
I mean, I thought they were Habaek's. But I guess they were yours.
Maksudku Habaek. Tapi kurasa itu milikmu.
Those are not the sneakers I saw last time.
Itu bukan sepatu yang kulihat.
Well...
Aku...
I'm not following at all.
Aku tak mengerti.
Isn't this a dream?
Bukankah ini mimpi?
No, I don't think so.
Kurasa tidak.
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
You're definitely Namsuri.
Kau jelas Namsuri.
What are you doing here?
Sedang apa di sini?
I thought you left.
Kukira kau pergi.
-I came back. -What?
- Aku kembali. - Apa?
You came back?
Kau kembali?
So, it's true.
Jadi, itu benar.
Well, what happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
-Go that way. -Pardon?
- Ke sana. - Apa?
Yes, My Lord.
Ya, Tuan.
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
He came back...
Dia kembali...
because he missed me.
karena merindukanku.
Why did you bring that weird lady with you?
Kenapa kau bawa wanita aneh itu?
Last time, she said she was looking for a part-time helper.
Terakhir kali, dia bilang mencari pembantu paruh waktu.
So I asked about it with my resident registration card.
Aku menanyakannya dengan KTP-ku.
-"A part-time helper"? -Yes.
- Pembantu? - Ya.
She said all I have to do is sit in her office all day.
Katanya aku hanya duduk di kantornya seharian.
She said she gets inspired by me.
Katanya dia terinspirasi olehku.
-What? -She said I inspire her.
- Apa? - Katanya aku menginspirasi dia.
She said her psychic abilities keep coming and going.
Dia bilang kemampuan cenayangnya datang dan pergi.
She's exactly like you.
Dia mirip sekali denganmu.
She said she feels something from me.
Katanya dia merasakan sesuatu dariku.
Back then, I avoided her because I was scared.
Dulu aku menghindar karena takut.
But I thought I should give it a try.
Tapi kucoba saja.
But why?
Kenapa?
All right, fine. Do your best.
Baiklah. Lakukan yang terbaik.
I think we'll need a lot of money.
Kita butuh lebih banyak uang lagi.
He came back to say goodbye?
Dia kembali untuk berpamitan?
So-a!
So-a.
Stop it.
Hentikan.
Yeom-mi.
Yeom-mi.
Why does everything have to be so difficult for you?
Kenapa semua harus rumit denganmu?
You see,
Aku...
I feel so guilty every time I see you.
merasa bersalah setiap melihatmu.
I'm the youngest daughter of a rich family.
Aku putri bungsu keluarga kaya.
My family will be fine for three more generations
Keluargaku akan baik selama tiga generasi
even if I do whatever I want to do.
bahkan jika aku hidup sesukaku.
Even if I do as I please,
Walaupun hidup sesukaku,
my life is still very beautiful and enjoyable.
hidupku sangat indah dan menyenangkan.
Because of that, I sometimes feel guilty when I see you.
Karenanya, kadang aku merasa bersalah saat melihatmu.
It doesn't happen that often, though.
Itu tak sering terjadi.
That's why I truly want you to become happy.
Karena itu, aku sungguh ingin kau bahagia.
That way, I won't have to feel guilty anymore.
Dengan begitu, aku tak perlu merasa bersalah lagi.
Yeom-mi.
Yeom-mi.
So-a!
So-a.
They're weird.
Mereka aneh.
Hey.
Hai.
Where did you go?
Ke mana kau pergi?
Did your friend leave?
Temanmu sudah pergi?
Yes.
Ya.
I'm on my way to see Mura.
Aku mau menemui Mura.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I'll see you later, then.
Sampai jumpa.
But why do you need to see her?
Kenapa harus menemuinya?
-I have something to say to her. -I see.
- Ada yang ingin kutanyakan. - Baik.
All right.
Baiklah.
Wait, what do you need to say to her?
Apa yang mau kau katakan?
You don't need to know.
Kau tak perlu tahu.
Okay. Bye, then.
Baiklah. Sampai jumpa.
Wait.
Tunggu.
Is it something important?
Apa itu hal yang penting?
-Hello? -What is this about?
- Halo? - Apa ini?
-Are you jealous? -What?
- Kau cemburu? - Apa?
-No, of course not. -It sounds like you're jealous.
- Tidak. - Tampaknya kau cemburu.
No, not at all.
Tidak sama sekali.
I'll never be jealous of your goddess friend.
Aku tak akan cemburu kepada teman dewimu.
Gosh, I'm a very rational person.
Aku orang yang sangat rasional.
Really?
Sungguh?
I'm the type of god who gets jealous of your male friends,
Aku dewa yang cemburu pada teman priamu,
so bear that in mind.
jadi, ingat itu.
I'm not rational.
Aku tidak rasional.
Come to think of it,
Kalau dipikir-pikir...
I think I can get jealous, too, from time to time.
kurasa aku juga bisa cemburu sesekali.
Can I hang up now?
Boleh aku tutup?
I have my part-time job today, so I'm heading out now. See you later.
Aku kerja paruh waktu hari ini. Aku mau pergi. Dah.
A part-time job?
Kerja paruh waktu?
I'm on my way to see a male human friend.
Aku mau menemui teman pria.
What? What are you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
Why can't I hear you properly?
Kenapa suaramu tidak jelas?
What? "Jealous"?
Apa? Cemburu?
-Hi. -Dr. Yun!
- Hai. - Dokter Yun!
What? What's wrong?
Ada apa?
Hey.
Hai.
Hey, what happened? The building has been sold?
Hai, apa yang terjadi?
The owner of the building suddenly sold it.
Pemilik gedung tiba-tiba menjualnya.
And the new owner said that we can just stay here.
Pemilik barunya bilang kita bisa tinggal.
He thinks having a clinic in the building will increase its value.
Katanya klinik di gedung akan meningkatkan nilainya.
Really?
Sungguh?
He even lowered our deposit and rent, saying that it's outrageously high.
Dan menurunkan deposit dan sewanya,
He also promised that he'll never kick us out.
Dia juga berjanji tak akan mengusir kita.
Are you serious?
Kau serius?
How can he be so kind?
Bagaimana dia bisa begitu baik?
Shouldn't we go and say hello?
Haruskah kita mengunjunginya?
He said he'll come by and meet all the tenants soon.
Katanya dia mau bertemu semua penyewa.
You should just take it easy this week.
Kau tenang saja minggu ini.
-Let's reopen next week. -Okay, sounds good.
- Kita buka minggu depan. - Bagus.
Let's think of it as a fresh start and do our best.
Anggap itu awal baru dan lakukan yang terbaik.
-Let's be passionate! -Okay.
- Ayo semangat! - Baiklah.
Let's do a good job.
Ayo lakukan dengan baik.
Tell me why Biryeom is acting that way.
Kenapa Biryeom begitu?
Tell me why he's going bonkers!
Katakan kenapa dia jadi gila!
It's because of me.
Itu karena aku.
-What? -That is all I can tell you.
- Apa? - Hanya itu yang bisa kukatakan.
What could it be?
Apa itu?
Your body double just finished shooting.
Penggantimu baru selesai syuting.
You have one night scene left,
Masih ada satu adegan malam,
but I think you need to come now because we need to get you prepared.
tapi kemarilah karena kami harus mempersiapkanmu.
Okay.
Baik.
And you got some gifts from your fans. I'll put them in your car when you arrive.
Ada hadiah dari fanmu. Akan kutaruh di mobilmu saat tiba.
Gifts?
Hadiah?
I told you not to accept anything.
- Kubilang jangan terima apa pun. - Mereka bersikeras, aku tak bisa menolak.
Okay.
Baik.
She's so weird. What kind of celebrity bans her fans from giving gifts?
Dia aneh. Selebritas macam apa yang melarang fan beri hadiah?
Don't say that. I like that attitude of hers.
Jangan begitu. Aku suka sikapnya.
What if she just throws them out?
Kalau dia buang?
Where are you?
Di mana kau?
Why do you ask?
Kenapa?
Where were you last night?
Di mana kau semalam?
Just get to the point.
Langsung ke intinya.
I need to talk to you.
Aku perlu bicara.
I have to go to a shoot, so come to Beriwon...
Aku syuting, datanglah ke Beriwon...
-No. Let's meet-- -Let's meet at Beriwon Resort.
- Tidak... - Di Resor Beriwon.
-No, let's just meet-- -I'm leaving now.
- Tidak, kita... - Aku ke sana.
-Are you done? -Yes.
- Sudah selesai? - Ya.
But I didn't see Mr. Min all day.
Aku tak melihat Pak Min seharian.
-He's away on a business trip. -I see.
- Dia ada urusan bisnis. - Begitu.
The feedback from the employees has been great.
Umpan balik dari karyawan sangat bagus. Katanya membantu mengatasi stres.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
You shouldn't be thanking me.
Jangan berterima kasih padaku.
I'm just doing it to pay off my debt.
Aku lakukan untuk melunasi utang.
-You seem happy today. -A miracle happened.
- Kau tampak senang hari ini. - Keajaiban terjadi.
My clinic can stay in the building.
Klinikku boleh tinggal di gedung itu.
We have a new landlord now,
Kami punya pemilik baru. Dia turunkan deposit dan sewa kami.
Really?
Sungguh?
-Not many people are like that these days. -I know.
- Tak banyak orang begitu belakangan ini. - Ya.
I should buy a big watermelon for him and go thank him in person.
Aku harus beli semangka besar untuknya dan berterima kasih langsung.
You probably can't have dinner with me this evening, right?
Kau tak bisa makan malam bersamaku nanti?
-No, I have-- -Right, I'm sure you have plans.
- Tidak, aku... - Benar, kau punya rencana.
-I'm not lying. -I know.
- Aku tak bohong. - Aku tahu.
I never said you were.
Aku tak menuduh.
I'm getting this feeling
Aku merasa...
that you probably won't be available for dinner
kau mungkin tak bisa makan malam bersama
for quite some time.
untuk waktu yang cukup lama.
I'll wait.
Aku tunggu.
You have a knack for enduring things, right?
Kau berbakat untuk bertahan, 'kan?
I'm good at waiting.
Aku hebat dalam menunggu.
Let's go. I'll walk you out.
Ayo. Akan kuantar.
The new owner of that building must be a cool guy.
Pemilik baru gedung itu pasti keren.
A gentleman with a warm heart.
Pria dengan hati yang hangat.
Someone who's got class.
Orang yang berkelas.
And I'm pretty sure he's quite good-looking.
Aku yakin dia cukup tampan.
I understand and agree with everything else,
Aku setuju dengan yang lain,
but what is your reason for assuming that he's good-looking?
tapi apa alasanmu menganggap dia tampan?
Aren't you being biased?
Bukankah kau bias?
There's no reason, and I'm not biased. It's just a prediction.
Tak ada alasan dan aku tak bias.
-I'm psychic. -What?
- Aku cenayang. - Apa?
-Gosh, that'd drive me nuts. -Sorry?
- Itu membuatku gila.
Stand still. I'm starting to feel antsy because of you.
Diam. Aku mulai merasa gatal karenamu.
-Thank you. -I feel much better now.
- Terima kasih. - Aku lebih baik sekarang.
What are you doing here?
Sedang apa kau di sini?
He's my friend.
Dia temanku.
What's up?
Ada apa?
You're one busy lady, So-a.
Kau wanita yang sibuk, So-a.
What?
Apa?
I'm not here to talk about Habaek.
Aku bukan mau bicara soal Habaek.
I'm just annoyed...
Aku hanya kesal
to see our servant hanging out with a prick like you.
melihat pelayan kami bergaul dengan bajingan sepertimu.
What are you doing right now?
Kau sedang apa?
There's one more thing that annoys me.
Ada satu hal lagi yang mengusikku.
It's the thought of you hanging out with him,
Memikirkan kau bergaul dengannya
despite knowing who he really is.
meski tahu siapa dia sebenarnya.
Is he your insurance? Do you plan to replace Habaek with him?
Apa dia asuransimu? Kau akan ganti Habaek dengannya?
What...
Apa...
-What are you saying-- -Get away from him!
- Apa maksudmu... - Jauhi dia!
I can't stand this.
Aku tak tahan lagi.
Let's stop playing petty tricks.
Mari berhenti bermain trik.
-How about we have a real showdown? -What's your reason for doing this?
Mau langsung saja?
My reason?
Alasanku?
Your very existence is my reason.
Keberadaanmu adalah alasanku.
I asked you for a reason.
Aku tanya alasannya.
You won't get what you want until you convince me with a good reason.
Kau tak akan dapatkan keinginanmu sampai kau beri alasan yang bagus.
Common sense, justice,
Alasanku akal sehat, keadilan,
and wanting to get rid of abnormal things. Let's just put it that way.
dan keinginan untuk menyingkirkan hal tak normal.
I don't like the fact
Aku tak suka kenyataan bahwa
that an abnormal being like you exists in this world.
makhluk abnormal sepertimu ada di dunia ini.
I'm just going to tolerate that kind of criticism.
Aku hanya akan menerima kritik semacam itu.
Do you think you'll have your way?
Apa kau akan dapatkan keinginanmu?
Will you let me go... if I let you hit me until you feel better?
Maukah kau melepasku jika kau memukulku sampai puas?
Of course not.
Tentu tidak.
I'm going to make you pay for your sins, even if that means...
Akan kubuat kau membayar dosamu bahkan jika itu berarti...
I must change the laws of the divine realm.
aku harus ubah hukum alam suci.
I never committed any sins!
Aku tak pernah berbuat dosa!
Yes.
Ya.
That's what it is. The fact that you don't know what you did.
Begitulah adanya. Kau tak tahu perbuatanmu.
That's my reason.
Itu alasanku.
I hate myself because of you.
Aku benci diriku karenamu.
That's what's driving me so crazy.
Itu yang membuatku gila.
And I've already told you my last reason.
Aku sudah memberitahumu alasan terakhirku.
I just hate you.
Aku hanya membencimu.
Jingeon, I won't forgive you if you interfere.
Jingeon, aku tak akan memaafkanmu jika ikut campur.
I can't give you a single penny, so get lost.
Tidak satu sen pun, pergilah.
-It's the King's order. -Whatever.
- Ini perintah raja. - Terserah.
Does the King have the right to steal money?
Apa Raja berhak mencuri uang?
I shall punish you when I return to the Land of Water.
Kau akan kuhukum saat kembali ke Negeri Air.
Sure. Just know that I'll freeze and crush your tongue before you do that.
Ya. Akan kubekukan dan kuhancurkan lidahmu sebelum itu.
I can't beg because I'm a king.
Raja tak bisa mengemis.
That's not the only thing you can't do. You can't do anything in this world.
Bukan cuma itu.
-Yes? -Where are you?
- Ya? - Di mana kau?
Bin... Ahn Bin is...
Ahn Bin...
What's wrong?
Ada apa?
Bin just took Mr. Shin. He just took him against his will.
Bin membawa Pak Shin. Dia menculiknya.
What are you talking about? Slow down.
Apa? Pelan-pelan.
What's up?
Ada apa?
-Let's stop. -No.
- Hentikan. - Tidak.
Neither of us can die anyway,
Kita tak bisa mati, jadi,
so we should fight until one of us is close to dying.
kita bertarung sampai salah satu nyaris mati.
You're wrong.
Kau salah.
Have you forgotten? I'm capable of...
Apa kau lupa? Aku mampu...
killing you guys.
membunuh kalian.
Isn't that why you suggested we fight without using our powers?
Itukah sebabnya kau mau kita bertarung tanpa kekuatan?
Jingeon.
Jingeon.
I told you to stay out of this!
Kubilang jangan ikut campur!
You're...
Kau...
Yes. Do you get it now?
Ya. Apa kau mengerti sekarang?
Do you remember who you killed?
Ingat siapa yang kau bunuh?
Do you now realize what your sin is?
Kini kau sadar apa dosamu?
Why have you kept it from me all this time?
Kenapa kau merahasiakannya?
I shouldn't have gone. I've regretted it thousands of times.
Seharusnya aku tak pergi. Aku menyesalinya.
Let it go. I know something is weighing on your mind.
Lepaskan. Aku tahu ada yang membebani pikiranmu.
-He's like you guys, isn't he? -He's not like us.
- Dia seperti kalian? - Tidak.
Ms. Yun, did we perhaps cross paths in the past?
Nona Yun. Apa kita pernah berjumpa di masa lalu?
I told you to keep in mind that I can be very jealous
Kubilang aku bisa sangat cemburu pada teman priamu.
Is this also jealousy?
Ini juga cemburu?
Just let him have her. That'll be better for her too.
Biar dia memilikinya. Lebih baik baginya.
-Mr. Shin. -That can't be.
- Pak Shin. - Tidak mungkin.
-Look at me. -Let go of me!
- Lihat aku. - Lepas!
-Stay still. -Are you with him right now?
- Diam. - Apa kau bersamanya?
-Did something happen? -Come home now.
- Apa terjadi sesuatu? - Pulang sekarang.
Don't come any closer. Please!
Jangan mendekatiku. Kumohon!